<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Threads Of Life</title>
    <link>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Threads Of Life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 18:42:25 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to deal with impostor syndrome</title>
      <link>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/how-to-deal-with-impostor-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 18:42:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/how-to-deal-with-impostor-syndrome/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone!
Impostor syndrome is very common these days and can affect anyone irrespective of gender, age or social status. According a recent study, 9 to 82% of people experience impostor syndrome. Believe it or not, impostor syndrome is for real and affects the lives of many. For those you who might want to know more about the origins of this syndrome I would recommend reading this paper. Common signs of impostor syndrome  Self doubt Fear that you won&amp;rsquo;t live up to expectations Self sabotage &amp;amp; negative thinking Crediting your success to external factors  It&#39;s important to identify these signs as early as possible and learn to deal with them using effective techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movie Review : The French Connection (1971)</title>
      <link>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/movie-review-the-french-connection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 21:03:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/movie-review-the-french-connection/</guid>
      <description>There are times when a thriller manages to keep you on the edge of your seat! ‘The French Connection’, based on the book written by Robin Moore, is one such classic American drama that takes you back to the old days when cops chased crooks in ancient cars with thrills and lots of action.
The story is about two New York Police Department detectives Jimmy &amp;ldquo;Popeye&amp;rdquo; Doyle, played by veteran actor Gene Hackman and his partner &amp;ldquo;Cloudy&amp;rdquo; Russo, played by Roy Scheider, who manage to narrow down on a big narcotic deal that is going to take place in the city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My top 10 favorite Marvel movies till date</title>
      <link>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/my-top-10-favorite-marvel-movies-till-date/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 09:58:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/my-top-10-favorite-marvel-movies-till-date/</guid>
      <description>Well, I have seen every Marvel movie atleast five to six times. Hence, choosing my top 10 Marvel movies is definitely not going to be an easy job 😅. So then without further ado let&amp;rsquo;s start ranking them in descending order.
10. Ant Man 9. Guardians of the Galaxy 8. Thor - Dark World 7. Captain America: The Winter Soldier 6. Iron Man 2 5. Captain Marvel 4. Doctor Strange 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My quarantine story</title>
      <link>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/my-quarantine-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 21:12:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/my-quarantine-story/</guid>
      <description>(Prelude)
As we boarded the penultimate flight from SriLanka to India, I had mixed feelings. The number of deaths were on the rise and new COVID-19 cases were being reported each day across the globe. Finally, in the wee hours of 22nd March 2020, I reached Mumbai just in the nick of time. Luckily, I had not got the home quarantine stamp on my hands but there was a fear as to whether I would be allowed entry in our housing complex considering the return from a foreign land.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to plan a solo trip</title>
      <link>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/how-to-plan-a-solo-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 10:02:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/how-to-plan-a-solo-trip/</guid>
      <description>The journey of a thousand miles begins with a single step! 😄
Solo traveling can be fun especially when you have planned it well. In the month of April 2019 when all my efforts in convincing my friends for an international tour had gone in vain, I decided to take up the solo path and started planning for my next trip. Apart from the basics like choosing the right destination, booking the right accommodation, scouting for cheaper flights and so on, there are also certain things that one needs to keep in mind while planning a solo trip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My top 5 iconic moments from &#39;The Social Network&#39;</title>
      <link>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/my-top-5-iconic-moments-from-the-social-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 19:45:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/my-top-5-iconic-moments-from-the-social-network/</guid>
      <description>The movie Social Network has to be one of the most amazing movies that I have ever seen in my life. It was based on the book The Accidental Billionaries by Ben Mezrich.
There are so many great moments in this film. The brilliant screenplay by Aaron Sorkin coupled with apt dialogues make most scenes memorable even today. The entire cast of the film including the main protagonist Jesse Eisenberg (as Mark Zuckerberg in the movie) have played their role to perfection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: It&#39;s Not about the Bike: My Journey Back to Life</title>
      <link>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/book-review-its-not-about-the-bike/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 20:50:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/book-review-its-not-about-the-bike/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Success is due to our stretching to the challenges of life. Failure comes when we shrink from them.&amp;rdquo;
These words of John C. Maxwell are apt to describe a man&amp;rsquo;s journey from pain and discomfort to heartfelt success. Lance Armstrong needs no introduction. A world famous athlete who rode his bike a record seven consecutive times between 1999 and 2005 at the Tour de France.
The book discusses Armstrong&amp;rsquo;s life and how he struggled through cancer and emerged victorious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goku or Vegeta - Who do you like the most?</title>
      <link>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/goku-or-vegeta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 08:53:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/goku-or-vegeta/</guid>
      <description>Ever felt the need to have an endless debate! 😀
Well, if you are a Dragonball fan then perhaps this could just be the ideal topic 😆
I remember watching the first episode on TV back in high school and ever since then I have watched the various sagas multiple times. Each character in the anime is amazing but many of us would always remember the most prominent ones. So, basically as a part of this anime we have two main characters namely : Goku (Son Goku)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why one should definitely watch &#39;Interstellar&#39;?</title>
      <link>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/why-one-should-definitely-watch-interstellar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 09:56:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/why-one-should-definitely-watch-interstellar/</guid>
      <description>Picture this!
An ex-NASA pilot embarks on a space mission along with a team of researchers to find a new planet for humans leaving behind his 10-year-old daughter Murph (played by Jessica Chastain), 15-year-old son Tom and father-in-law. Interstellar is a science fiction film directed by Christopher Nolan that explores the psychological and emotional state of a man whose life revolves around his space journey and family. The movie also depicts the love and admiration a daughter has for her father who promises her that he will return back (which he eventually does!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to utilize the time post your final engineering exam</title>
      <link>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/how-to-utilize-the-time-post-your-final-engineering-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 19:51:53 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/how-to-utilize-the-time-post-your-final-engineering-exam/</guid>
      <description>Final semester exams done and the long vacation begins&amp;hellip;!!!
(After 2 weeks or so)
Friend: Hey dude, wassup these days?
You: Hi! What are doing in your vacation? Any news about your joining date in XYZ company?
For those of you who are really bored right now, just try copy-pasting any one of the above conversations in your favorite messaging app chat search and you’ll probably be surprised with the number of results that come up.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
