<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Threads Of Life</title>
    <link>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/categories/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Threads Of Life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 18:42:25 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.karanbalkar.com/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to deal with impostor syndrome</title>
      <link>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/how-to-deal-with-impostor-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 18:42:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/how-to-deal-with-impostor-syndrome/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone!
Impostor syndrome is very common these days and can affect anyone irrespective of gender, age or social status. According a recent study, 9 to 82% of people experience impostor syndrome. Believe it or not, impostor syndrome is for real and affects the lives of many. For those you who might want to know more about the origins of this syndrome I would recommend reading this paper. Common signs of impostor syndrome  Self doubt Fear that you won&amp;rsquo;t live up to expectations Self sabotage &amp;amp; negative thinking Crediting your success to external factors  It&#39;s important to identify these signs as early as possible and learn to deal with them using effective techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My quarantine story</title>
      <link>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/my-quarantine-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 21:12:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/my-quarantine-story/</guid>
      <description>(Prelude)
As we boarded the penultimate flight from SriLanka to India, I had mixed feelings. The number of deaths were on the rise and new COVID-19 cases were being reported each day across the globe. Finally, in the wee hours of 22nd March 2020, I reached Mumbai just in the nick of time. Luckily, I had not got the home quarantine stamp on my hands but there was a fear as to whether I would be allowed entry in our housing complex considering the return from a foreign land.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A musical evening!</title>
      <link>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/a-musical-evening/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2014 10:06:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/a-musical-evening/</guid>
      <description>Last evening couldn&#39;t have been much better. It&#39;s not quite often that one witnesses ordinary people with extra-ordinary talent. World No Tobacco Day (WNTD) is observed around the world every year on May 31st. In order to spread the awareness of cancer, NGO Helping Hand had organized a special musical evening in Mumbai. The event saw eminent personalities including Mrs. Priya Dutt, Mrs. Manisha Koirala and Mr. Johny Joseph  felicitating cancer survivors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to utilize the time post your final engineering exam</title>
      <link>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/how-to-utilize-the-time-post-your-final-engineering-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 19:51:53 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.karanbalkar.com/posts/how-to-utilize-the-time-post-your-final-engineering-exam/</guid>
      <description>Final semester exams done and the long vacation begins&amp;hellip;!!!
(After 2 weeks or so)
Friend: Hey dude, wassup these days?
You: Hi! What are doing in your vacation? Any news about your joining date in XYZ company?
For those of you who are really bored right now, just try copy-pasting any one of the above conversations in your favorite messaging app chat search and you’ll probably be surprised with the number of results that come up.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
